Guide to the UNITE HERE! Local 8 Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
UNITE HERE! Local 8 records
approximately 1900-2007
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
6290
6290-001
UNITE HERE (Organization).$bLocal 8
32.99 cubic feet 37 boxes and 1 folder
Records of UNITE HERE! Local 8, a union representing workers in the hospitality industry in Oregon and Washington as well as the records of earlier local craft unions which merged to form it.
UNITE HERE is an international labor union in the United States and Canada with roughly 300,000 active members. The union represents workers in the hotel, food service, laundry, warehouse, and casino gaming industries. The union was formed by a 2004 merger of two international unions: the Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees (UNITE) and Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE).
In 2005, UNITE HERE withdrew from the AFL-CIO and joined the Change to Win Federation, along with several other unions, including the Teamsters, Service Employees International Union (SEIU) and the UFCW. In May 2009, union president Bruce Raynor (originally from UNITE) left UNITE HERE, taking with him numerous local unions and between 105,000 and 150,000 members, mostly garment workers and a labor-owned bank, Amalgamated Bank. They formed a new SEIU affiliate called Workers United. In 2009, UNITE HERE re-affiliated with the AFL-CIO.
HERE local unions in larger cities were typically organized on a craft basis, with separate organizations for job classifications such as cooks, waitresses, waiters, bartenders and hotel employees. Where separate craft local unions existed, there was often a Local Joint Executive Board which coordinated between the craft locals. UNITE HERE! Local 8 was formed in 2004 as a result of the merger of the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE) and the Hotel and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE). It represents workers in the hospitality industry in Oregon and Washington. Local 8 of the Hotel, Motel and Restaurant Employees Union was formed in 1984 by a merger of Puget Sound-area locals 3, 33, 487, 551, and 596. Other local unions in Washington and Oregon later merged into Local 8 as well.
The UNITE HERE LOCAL 8 record group is arranged into 5 series. The remainder of the collection is arranged into 16 subgroups:
SERIES 1: MINUTES
SERIES 2: MEMBERSHIP RECORDS
SERIES 3: FINANCIAL RECORDS
SERIES 4: CONSTITUTIONS AND BYLAWS OF LOCAL 8 AND RELATED LOCAL UNIONS
SERIES 5: REFERENCE MATERIALS, ARTIFACTS AND EPHEMERA
SUBGROUP 1: SEATTLE JOINT LOCAL EXECUTIVE BOARD
SUBGROUP 2: COOKS AND ASSISTANTS LOCAL 33, SEATTLE
SUBGROUP 3: WAITRESSES LOCAL 240, SEATTLE
SUBGROUP 4: DINING ROOM EMPLOYEES LOCAL 3, SEATTLE
SUBGROUP 5: BARTENDERS LOCAL 487, SEATTLE
SUBGROUP 6: HOTEL, MOTEL AND CLUB SERVICE EMPLOYEES UNION LOCAL 551, SEATTLE
SUBGROUP 7: HOTEL, MOTEL AND RESTAURANT EMPLOYEES LOCAL 400, SPOKANE
SUBGROUP 8: TACOMA JOINT LOCAL EXECUTIVE BOARD
SUBGROUP 9: HOTEL, MOTEL AND RESTAURANT EMPLOYEES LOCAL 61, TACOMA
SUBGROUP 10: LOCAL 20, TACOMA
SUBGROUP 11: HOTEL AND RESTAURANT EMPLOYEES AND BARTENDERS LOCAL 791, ABERDEEN
SUBGROUP 12: CULINARY AND BEVERAGE WORKERS UNION LOCAL 529, BELLINGHAM
SUBGROUP 13: CULINARY WORKERS AND BARTENDERS UNION LOCAL 451, EVERETT
SUBGROUP 14: COOKS AND WAITERS CULINARY ALLIANCE LOCAL 730, BREMERTON
SUBGROUP 15: CULINARY WORKERS AND BARTENDERS LOCAL 596, RENTON
SUBGROUP 16: LOCAL 61 BUILDING CORPORATION
Union records in this collection consist primarily of meeting minutes, membership records, and financial records. The membership records are mainly in the form of dues ledgers, which record members' initiation date and dues payments as well as suspension and reinstatement dates and transfers between local unions. In some cases these ledgers record workers' home addresses and employers.
These records are organized in record subgroups corresponding to the local organization that created them.
Local 8 records in this collection have some overlap with the records of the local unions which merged to form it. Local 8 records include minutes (1974-1979), membership records (1971-1991), financial records (1978-1986), as well as constitutions and bylaws of related local unions (1927-1984).
Records from Seattle-area local unions include those from Cooks and Assistants, Local 33 (membership records, 1908-1977); Waitresses, Local 240 (membership records, 1900-1960; financial records, 1963-1970); Dining Room Employees, Local 3 - a merger of the Waiters Local 239 and Waitresses, Local 240 (membership records, 1950-1970); Bartenders Union, Local 487 (meeting minutes, 1942-1971; membership records, 1918-1967; financial records, 1919-1934); and Hotel, Motel and Club Service Employees, Local 551 (membership records, 1947-1970). Records of the Seattle Joint Executive Board include meeting attendance records (1915-1976), financial records (1903-1974), and collective bargaining records (1957-1975).
Spokane, Local 400 records include collective bargaining records (1943-1979) and legal records (1980-1983).
Tacoma Joint Local Executive Board records include correspondence and legal records (1969-1976). Records from Tacoma, Local 61 include meeting minutes (1902-1979), membership records (1901-1953), financial records (1901-1969) and collective bargaining records (1917-1970). Local 61, together with Bartenders Union, Local 711, merged to form Local 20 in 1979; this organization is represented here by a small group of records. Tacoma Local 61 established the Local 61 Building Corporation to own and manage its union hall in downtown Tacoma, which it purchased in 1945. Records of this corporation include minutes, property and financial records, and correspondence related to the ownership of the building (1945-1976).
Other local union records include those from local unions in Aberdeen (Hotel and Restaurant Employees and Bartenders' Union, Local 791), Bellingham (Culinary and Beverage Workers Union, Local 529), Everett (Culinary Workers and Bartenders, Local 451), Bremerton (Cooks and Waiters Culinary Alliance, Local 730), and Renton (Culinary Workers and Bartenders, Local 596).
Access to portions of the collection is restricted. Contact University of Washington Libraries Special Collections for details.
Forms part of the Labor Archives of Washington.
Donated by UNITE HERE! Local 8
Bound issues of the Hotel and Restaurant Employees' International Alliance and Bartenders' International League of America's journal The Mixer and Server and its predecessor publication, The Catering Industry Employee, were removed from the collection and cataloged separately as a part of Special Collections' serials.
UNITE HERE (Organization).$bLocal 8$xHistory$vArchives; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees$xHistory$vArchives; Hotel Employees & Restaurant Employees International Union$xHistory$vArchives; Food industry and trade$xEmployees$xLabor unions$zWashington (State)$xHistory$vArchives; Labor$zWashington (State); Labor unions$zWashington (State); Labor movement$zWashington (State); Minutes (Records); Records (Documents); Business correspondence; Ephemera; Account books; Trial and arbitral proceedings; Ledgers (account books); Membership lists; Membership cards; Contract documents; Transcripts; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Labor Unions
- MINUTES, 1974-1979; SERIES 1 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Regular meeting and Executive Board minutes, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 1/1)
- MEMBERSHIP RECORDS, 1971-1991; SERIES 2 (Box-folder 1/2-5, 20/1, 33/1-9, 35/2-3, 36/1-4)
  - Membership ledger, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Membership ledger, 1977 (Box-folder 20/1)
  - Membership ledger, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 35/2)
  - Membership ledger, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 35/3)
  - Membership ledger, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 36/1)
  - Membership ledger, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 36/2)
  - Membership ledger, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 36/3)
  - Membership ledger, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 36/4)
  - Membership ledger, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 1/3)
    access restriction: SSNs
  - Name change ledger, 1971-1984 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Retired life members dues record, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Master member list, 1982 (Box-folder 33/1)
  - Master member list, 1983 (Box-folder 33/2)
  - Front of the house roster, 1983 (Box-folder 33/3)
  - Member roster, 1984 (Box-folder 33/4)
  - Tacoma Local 20 roster at time of merger, 1984 (Box-folder 33/5)
  - Master member list, 1985 (Box-folder 33/6)
  - Master member list, 1986 (Box-folder 33/7)
  - Shops file, 1986 (Box-folder 33/8)
  - Social security book, 1981-1991 (Box-folder 33/9)
- FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1978-1986; SERIES 3 (Box-folder 29/1-2)
  - General ledger, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 29/1)
  - Receipts ledger, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 29/2)
- CONSTITUTIONS AND BYLAWS OF LOCAL 8 AND RELATED LOCAL UNIONS, 1914-1984; SERIES 4 (Box-folder 2/1-13)
  - Bylaws of Hotel Employees & Restaurant Employees Union Local No. 8, 1984 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Bylaws and rules of order of Culinary Workers and Bartenders Local 451, Everett, 1950-1964 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Constitution and bylaws. Culinary Alliance and Beverage Dispensers Local 567, Olympia, 1963-1971 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Bylaws and rules of order, Bartenders Local No. 487, Seattle, 1954 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Bartenders Local No. 485, Spokane - bylaws, 1942-1966 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Hotel and Restaurant Employees Local 400, Spokane - bylaws, 1927-1976 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Hotel, Motel and Restaurant Employees Union Local 61, Tacoma - bylaws, 1950-1962 (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Bylaws of Hotel, Motel and Restaurant Employees and Bartenders Union Local 20, Tacoma, approximately 1970 (Box-folder 2/8)
  - Culinary Workers and Bartenders Union Local 425, Vancouver - bylaws, 1968 (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Bylaws and rules. Culinary and Beverage Workers Local No. 529, Whatcom and Skagit Counties, 1962 (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Bylaws of the Washington State Council of Culinary Workers, Bartenders, and Hotel Service Employees of the Hotel and Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union AFL-CIO, 1967-1976 (Box-folder 2/11)
  - Hotel and Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union constitution, 1957-1976 (Box-folder 2/12)
  - Manual of Hotel and Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union, 1958-1964 (Box-folder 2/13)
- REFERENCE MATERIALS, ARTIFACTS AND EPHEMERA, 1940-2010; SERIES 5 (Box-folder 19/23-35, 19/37-39, 33/14-15, 37/4, oversized folder 1)
  - Restaurant Employees Bartenders and Hotel Employees health care and vision car plan descriptions, 1973-1979 (Box-folder 19/23)
  - Sample bylaws for HERE local unions, Approximately 1960s (Box-folder 19/24)
  - Constitution and bylaws of Building Service Employees International Union, Approximately 1950s (Box-folder 19/25)
  - HERE roster of local unions, 1950 (Box-folder 19/26)
  - Port Angeles state convention group photograph, 1940 (Box-folder 19/27)
  - List of loaned documents, 1985 (Box-folder 19/28)
  - The Union for You (brochure), Approximately 1970s (Box-folder 19/29)
  - Contract and agreement, Joint Executive Board of Yakima, Locals 294 and 624, 1971 (Box-folder 19/30)
  - Contract and agreement Local 208, Pasco, 1977 (Box-folder 19/31)
  - Wage scale and agreement, Local 298, Wenatchee, 1971 (Box-folder 19/32)
  - Hotel restaurant bar employees agreement, Local 490, Lewiston, 1970 (Box-folder 19/33)
  - Contract and agreement between Oregon Food and Beverage President's Council and Portland HERE local unions, 1970 (Box-folder 19/34)
  - Agreements for union locals out of area, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 19/35)
  - Officers' reports and daily proceedings of the 36th general convention -- diamond jubilee, 1966 (Box-folder 19/37)
  - Allied food and beverage (journal), 1953 (Box-folder 19/38)
  - To live in dignity -- Pierce County labor, 1883-1989 (Box-folder 19/39)
  - Press clipping scrapbook, 1914-1919 (Box-folder 37/4)
  - Job dispatch notes, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 33/14)
  - Artifacts: Stop scabs badge and plastic noisemaker, approximately 2000s (Box-folder 33/15)
  - 43rd H.E.R.E. Convention poster, 2001 (Box os 1)
  - UNITE HERE Local 8 round parade placard, approximately 2000s (Box os 1)
- SEATTLE JOINT LOCAL EXECUTIVE BOARD, 1903-1976; SUBGROUP 1 (Box-folder 2/14-26, 29/3-30/2)
  - MINUTES, 1915-1937, 1973-1976; SERIES 1 (Box-folder 2/14-15)
    - Roll call record; also contains house card deposit ledger, 1934-1940, 1915-1937 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Roll call ledger, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 2/15)
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1903-1976; SERIES 2 (Box-folder 2/16-23, 29/3-30/2)
    - Organizational fund ledger, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 29/3)
    - Organizational fund ledger, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Cash book, 1903-1918 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Cash book, 1918-1924 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Cash book, 1925-1932 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Cash book, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Receipt and expense ledger, 1932-1937 (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Cash book, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 29/4)
    - Cash book, 1964-1969 (Box-folder 30/1)
    - Cash book, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 30/2)
    - House card deposit fund ledger, 1940-1949 (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Payroll record / local donation record, 1938-1941 (Box-folder 2/23)
      Access restriction: includes SSN
  - COLLECTIVE BARGAINING RECORDS, 1957-1975; SERIES 3 (Box-folder 2/24-26)
    - Tavern working agreement and wage scale, Seattle Joint Local Executive Board, 1966 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Working agreement and wage scale between Seattle Joint Executive Board and Washington State Restaurant Association et al., 1957-1972 (Box-folder 2/25)
    - Wage scale and working rules, Seattle Joint Executive Board and Seattle Department Store Association, Inc., 1957-1975 (Box-folder 2/26)
- COOKS AND ASSISTANTS LOCAL 33, SEATTLE, 1908-1977; SUBGROUP 2 (Box-folder 3/1-9/5, 28/1, 30/3-4, 34/1-2, 34/5)
  - MEMBERSHIP RECORDS, SERIES 1
    - Dues ledger, 1908 (Box-folder 34/1)
    - Dues ledger, 1909 (Box-folder 34/2)
    - Dues ledger, 1915 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Dues ledger, 1916 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Dues ledger, 1917 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Dues ledger, 1918 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Dues ledger, 1921 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Dues ledger, 1922 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Dues ledger, 1924 (Box-folder 34/3)
    - Dues ledger, 1925 (Box-folder 34/4)
    - Dues ledger, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Dues ledger, 1929 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Dues ledger, 1930 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Dues ledger, 1931 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Dues ledger, 1932 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Dues ledger, 1933 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Dues ledger, 1934 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Dues ledger, 1935 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Dues ledger, 1936 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Dues ledger, 1937 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Dues ledger, 1938 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Dues ledger, 1939 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Dues ledger, 1940 (Box-folder 6/1)
      Access restrictions: includes SSNs
    - Dues ledger (1 of 3), 1941 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Dues ledger (2 of 3), 1941 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Dues ledger (3 of 3), 1941 (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Dues ledger (1 of 2), 1942 (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Dues ledger (2 of 2), 1942 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Dues ledger A-L, 1943 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Dues ledger M-Z, 1943 (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Dues ledger L-Z, 1944 (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Dues ledger A-K, 1945 (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Dues ledger L-Z, 1945 (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Dues ledger A-Z, 1946 (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Dues ledger H-O, 1946 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Dues Ledger P-Z, 1946 (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Dues ledger, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Membership record cards, 1947-1970; 3 reels of 16 mm diazo microfilm (Box-folder 31/1)
    - Dues ledger, 1950-1975; A-Z; diazo microfiche (Box-folder 28/1)
    - Membership ledger, 1941-1944 (Box-folder 34/5)
    - Membership ledger, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 30/3)
    - Membership ledger, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 30/4)
- WAITRESSES LOCAL 240, SEATTLE, 1900-1973; SUBGROUP 3 (Box-folder 2/27-28, 10/1-12/6, 16/1-2, 31/2-4)
  - MEMBERSHIP RECORDS, 1900-1973; SERIES 1 (Box-folder 10/1-12/6, 31/2-4)
    - Dues ledger, 1900 (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Dues ledger, 1901 (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Dues ledger, 1902 (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Dues ledger, 1903 (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Dues ledger, 1904 (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Dues ledger, 1905 (Box-folder 10/6)
    - Dues ledger, 1906 (Box-folder 10/7)
    - Dues ledger (1 of 2), 1907 (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Dues ledger (2 of 2), 1907 (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Dues ledger, 1908 (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Dues ledger, 1909 (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Dues ledger, 1910 (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Dues ledger, 1911 (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Dues ledger, 1912 (Box-folder 12/2)
    - Dues ledger, 1913 (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Dues ledger, 1946-1955; 5 reels of 16 mm diazo microfilm (Box-folder 31/2)
    - Inactive member cards, 1936-1946; 2 reels of 16 mm diazo microfilm (Box-folder 31/3)
    - Inactive member cards, 1946-1960; 2 reels of 16 mm diazo microfilm (Box-folder 31/4)
    - Membership roster, 1972 (Box-folder 12/4)
    - Membership roster, 1973 (Box-folder 12/5)
    - Membership book of Eleanor Carter, 1918-1941 (Box-folder 12/6)
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1963-1970; SERIES 2 (Box-folder 2/27-28, 16/1-2)
    - General ledger, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 16/1)
    - General ledger, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Audit reports, 1968 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Audit reports, 1969 (Box-folder 2/28)
- DINING ROOM EMPLOYEES LOCAL 3, SEATTLE, 1950-1970; SUBGROUP 4 (Box-folder 31/5)
  - Dues ledgers, 1950-1970; 7 reels 16mm diazo microfilm (Box-folder 31/5)
    Access restriction: includes SSNs
- BARTENDERS LOCAL 487, SEATTLE, 1918-1971; SUBGROUP 5 (Box-folder 13/1-15/20, 16/3-4, 30/5-6)
  - MINUTES, 1942-1971; SERIES 1 (Box-folder 13/1-15/1)
    - Local 487 membership meeting minutes, 1942-1947 (Box-folder 13/1)
    - Local 487 membership meeting minutes, 1947-1952 (Box-folder 13/2)
    - Local 487 membership meeting minutes, 1952-1960 (Box-folder 13/3)
    - Local 487 membership meeting minutes, 1960-1971 (Box-folder 14/1)
    - Executive Board minutes, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Executive Board minutes, 1945-1948 (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Executive Board minutes, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Executive Board minutes, 1950-1954 (Box-folder 15/1)
  - MEMBERSHIP RECORDS, 1918-1967; SERIES 2 (Box-folder 15/2-15/10, 16/3-4, 30/5-6)
    - Dues ledger, 1918 (Box-folder 15/2)
    - Dues ledger, 1919 (Box-folder 15/3)
    - Dues ledger, 1920 (Box-folder 15/4)
    - Dues ledger, 1921 (Box-folder 15/5)
    - Dues ledger, 1923-1925 (Box-folder 15/6)
    - Dues ledger, 1930-1933 (Box-folder 15/7)
    - Dues ledger, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 15/8)
    - Membership ledger, 1938-1949 (Box-folder 15/9)
    - Membership ledger, 1948-1954 (Box-folder 30/5)
    - Membership ledger, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 30/6)
    - Membership ledger, 1961-1967 (Box-folder 16/3)
    - Membership applications, initiation fee refunded, 1944-1953 (Box-folder 16/4)
      Restricted access: includes SSNs
    - Member sign/in record, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 15/10)
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1918-1934; SERIES 3 (Box-folder 15/11-20)
    - Cash book, 1919-1925 (Box-folder 15/11)
    - Cash book, 1928-1931 (Box-folder 15/12)
    - Day book, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 15/13)
    - Day book, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 15/14)
    - Day book, 1920-1921 (Box-folder 15/15)
    - Day book, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 15/16)
    - Day book, 1923-1925 (Box-folder 15/17)
    - Day book, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 15/18)
    - Day book, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 15/19)
    - Day book, 1931-1934 (Box-folder 15/20)
- HOTEL, MOTEL AND CLUB SERVICE EMPLOYEES UNION LOCAL 551, SEATTLE, 1939-1970; SUBGROUP 6 (Box-folder 16/5, 31/6)
  - MEMBERSHIP RECORDS, 1947-1970; SERIES 1 (Box-folder 31/6)
    - Membership cards, 1947-1970; 2 reels 16mm diazo microfilm (Box-folder 31/6)
      Privacy: includes SSNs
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1939-1940; SERIES 2 (Box-folder 16/5)
    - Day book, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 16/5)
- HOTEL, MOTEL AND RESTAURANT EMPLOYEES LOCAL 400, SPOKANE, 1943-1983; SUBGROUP 7 (Box-folder 2/29-35, 17/1-9, 19/22,)
  - Local officials group photograph, 1972 (Box-folder 2/35)
  - Spokane Area Hotel & Restaurant Employees Trust Fund summary plan description, 1979 (Box-folder 19/22)
  - COLLECTIVE BARGAINING RECORDS, 1943-1979; SERIES 1 (Box-folder 2/29-34)
    - Contract and agreement, Locals 400, 1943-1959 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - Contract and agreement, Locals 400 and 485, 1959-1965 (Box-folder 2/30)
    - Contract and agreement, Locals 400 and 485, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 2/31)
    - Contract and agreement, Locals 400 and 485, 1971 (Box-folder 2/32)
    - Contract and agreement, Locals 400 and 485, 1974 (Box-folder 2/33)
    - Contract and agreement, Locals 400 and 485, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 2/34)
  - LEGAL RECORDS, 1980-1983; SERIES 2 (Box-folder 17/1-9)
    - David Sandler vs. Guenther et al. (part 1 of 9), 1980-1983 (Box-folder 17/1)
    - David Sandler vs. Guenther et al. (part 2 of 9), 1980-1983 (Box-folder 17/2)
    - David Sandler vs. Guenther et al. (part 3 of 9), 1980-1983 (Box-folder 17/3)
    - David Sandler vs. Guenther et al. (part 4 of 9), 1980-1983 (Box-folder 17/4)
    - David Sandler vs. Guenther et al. (part 5 of 9), 1980-1983 (Box-folder 17/5)
    - David Sandler vs. Guenther et al. (part 6 of 9), 1980-1983 (Box-folder 17/6)
    - David Sandler vs. Guenther et al. (part 7 of 9), 1980-1983 (Box-folder 17/7)
    - David Sandler vs. Guenther et al. (part 8 of 9), 1980-1983 (Box-folder 17/8)
    - David Sandler vs. Guenther et al. (part 9 of 9), 1980-1983 (Box-folder 17/9)
- TACOMA JOINT LOCAL EXECUTIVE BOARD, 1969-1976; SUBGROUP 8 (Box-folder 17/10-18/6)
  - CORRESPONDENCE, 1971-1976; SERIES 1 (Box-folder 17/10-12)
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 17/10)
    - Bartenders Union Local 711, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 17/11)
    - Bartenders Union Local 711, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 17/12)
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1972-1974; SERIES 2 (Box-folder 17/13)
    - Financial reports and statements, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 17/13)
  - LEGAL RECORDS, 1969-1972; SERIES 3 (Box-folder 18/1-6)
    - Norma Tei vs. Local Joint Executive Board of Tacoma, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 18/1)
    - Strikers' reinstatement and back pay, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 18/2)
    - Sherwood Inn case, 1970 (Box-folder 18/3)
    - NLRB case 19/CB/1478, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 18/4)
    - NLRB case 19-CA-4477, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 18/5)
    - NLRB case 19-CA-4477, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 18/6)
- HOTEL, MOTEL AND RESTAURANT EMPLOYEES LOCAL 61, TACOMA, 1901-1979; SUBGROUP 9 (Box-folder 18/1-22, 19/1-20, 19/36, 20/2-21/2, 22/1-26/10, 26/15, 34/6-10)
  - MINUTES, 1902-1979; SERIES 1 (Box-folder 18/7-8, 19/1-20, 19/36, 20/2-21/2, 34/6-10)
    - Membership meeting minutes, 1902-1903 (Box-folder 34/6)
    - Membership meeting minutes, 1903-1915 (Box-folder 18/7)
    - Meeting minutes, 1906-1908 (Box-folder 34/7)
    - Meeting minutes, 1915-1918 (Box-folder 34/8)
    - Meeting minutes, 1922-1937 (Box-folder 34/9)
    - Meeting minutes, 1937-1941 (Box-folder 34/10)
    - Meeting minutes, 1942-1947 (Box-folder 20/2)
    - Meeting minutes, 1947-1951 (Box-folder 20/3)
    - Meeting minutes, 1951-1955 (Box-folder 21/1)
    - Meeting minutes, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Meeting minutes, 1964-1970 (Box-folder 35/1)
    - Membership meeting minutes, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 18/8)
    - Executive Board minutes, 1939-1942 (Box-folder 19/1)
    - Executive Board minutes, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 19/2)
    - Executive Board minutes, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 19/3)
    - Executive Board minutes, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 19/4)
    - Executive Board minutes, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 19/5)
    - Executive Board minutes, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 19/6)
    - Executive Board minutes, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 19/7)
    - Executive Board minutes, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 19/8)